Phone: 859-948-8361 Email: Rob.Quan@gmail.com GitHub: github.com/TheRobQ

Profile

Full-stack Web Developer and award-winning visual designer with over 15 years of expertise and a passion for implementing web funtionality that deliveres clean and engaging user experiences. I've led a team of 24 designers and shepherded major projects to completion.

Recent Web Projects

The Post

Technologies: React.js, Redux, Bootstrap, Knex.js, Express.js, Node. js, PosrgreSQL, JavaScript

- A full-stack proof of concept for https://pro-file.us/. Client was looking for a partner site that would allow users to create accounts and submit articles. App is built with React and Redux.
- Includes admin features for deleting articles and users. github.com/TheRobQ/thepost-frontend github.com/TheRobQ/postbackend theprofilepost.herokuapp.com/

Mappy Hour

Technologies: Express.js, Node.js, PostgreSQL, AJAX, Knex, HTML, CSS, jQuery. JavaScript

- A full-stack application that allows users to view information on local happy hours via Google Maps API.
- App allows users to create accounts and populate favorites.

https://mappyhour.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/TheRobQ/Q2-Project

D&D Fight Night

Technologies: HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript

- A web app for tracking initiative order for and D20-based games.
- Players and foers can be saved in local storage for later use.

http://initiativeapp.surge.sh/ https://github.com/TheRobQ/Q1-Project

Technical Skills

JavaScriptReact

■ Redux

- Node.js
- Express.js
- RESTful design
- HTML

■ PostgreSQL

- Agile ProcessjQuery
- CSS(+Bootstrap)
- Git workflow

Experience

Digital First Media | Daily Camera (May 2004 to Oct. 2017)

Design Director: May 2012 to Oct. 2017

- Oversaw design, editing and production for 12 newspapers in Colorado and out of state, including the Denver Post, Boulder Daily Camera, and the St. Paul Pioneer Press.
- Managed team of 24 designers. Monitored and appraised job performance, communicated expectations to my team and handled personnel issues.
- Built, updated and maintained publishing system's XML and CSS back end.
- Fostered and grew numerous relationships over a dozen client sites.
- Helped oversee the on-boarding of design for the St. Paul Pioneer Press and Denver Post. Coordinated move of all page building for two major metro newspapers. Converted page building from InDesign and built all XML and CSS for project based on existing InDesign stylesheets.

Assistant Design Director: July 2010 to May 2012

- Responsible for helping oversee and schedule a team of 15 designers.
- Coordinated page building for nine Colorado newspapers.
- Integrated staff from two other papers into the newly formed hub.

Designer: June 2004 to July 2012

- Primary 1A designer for the Boulder Daily Camera. Designed and edited news and feature sections; proofed all pages before printing.
- Edited and selected stories for publication from wire services.
- Consistently met deadlines and produced clean, accurate headlines.

University of Colorado

Adjunct Professor of Journalism: August 2012 to Present

- Teach the junior/senior-level editing and visual journalism course at CU-Boulder's school of journalism.
- Developed a curriculum for the class focused on storytelling, editing, AP style, design fundamentals, and Adobe InDesign.
- Implemented daily and unit lesson plans for class averaging 16 students.
- Achieved high faculty and course ratings from end-of-term student questionnaires.

Education & Awards

Galvanize Web Development Immersive

B.A. English, University of Kentucky | Maynard Editing Program

Awards: Colorado Press Association 2007 editorial design, 2013 general excellence